Siddharth Kumar

New York, New York

Data Engineer at Facebook

Summary

A data fanatic enabling data and product speak the same language. I enjoy building scalable applications to support data processing, implementing machine learning models and product analytics. Over the years I've gained experience working in early to mid-range startup environments, established companies and professional services organization.

Experience

Data Engineer at Facebook

August 2017 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Data Engineer at Airbnb

June 2014 - August 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Founding member of the Data Engineering team at Airbnb responsible for building the core data warehouse to track key business metrics for reporting and analytics

Work closely with Product Marketplace teams such as Search, Pricing and build real time data pipelines for Machine Learning models.

Responsible for building powerful data sets that help understand user click stream behavior.

Onboard new engineers to the team and work with cross functional data teams.

Sr. Consultant at Claraview (formerly Lunexa, acquired in 2013)

February 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Provide clients with business intelligence and data warehousing implementation and advisory services

Recent Engagements:

Disney Interactive, Playdom division - Solutions Architect

- Provide data integration and warehouse solutions for Disney mobile and social gaming division
- Vertica, Hadoop, bash, python

Visa Inc. - Hadoop Developer

- Map Reduce, Hive, HDFS, bash

Teradata Inc. - Aster Developer

- Implement a Digital Marketing Solution using Aster analytic functions such as npath, attribution and custom written functions using Aster Data Library implemented in Java.

Disney Interactive - ETL Developer

- Provide data integration services for Disney Interactive across Salesforce and Google Doubleclick systems.
- Salesforce API, Google DFP, DSM API, Hadoop, Hive, Talend, Vertica

OSI Restaurant Partners - SnapLogic Developer

- Provide Integration services for HR data using SnapLogic to provide near real time updates across heterogenous end points.

Data Warehouse Developer at CareerBuilder.com

April 2011 - February 2012 (11 months)

Member of the Data Architecture team to design and develop work flows to support BI services by consolidating data from heterogeneous data sources.

Provide services to handle big data using Hadoop/Hbase.

Service Owner for providing Predictive Analytics to the Sales team.

Service Owner for providing useful insight on customer purchase patterns and product performance using Machine Learning and Statistical approaches.

Interact with internal and external users to develop technical designs.

Software Engineer at Segmint

May 2010 - April 2011 (1 year)

Java developer to support Data Modeling and Information Retrieval.

Designing process flows for handling data transformations via Talend workflows and PL/PgSQL scripts.

Identify solutions for handling big data.

Applying Machine Learning algorithms for pattern recognition and Knowledge Discovery.

Building reports on JasperSoft for business users and analysts.

Teaching Assistant at University of Akron, Ohio

December 2008 - May 2009 (6 months)

Teaching Assistant to the Chair of Computer Science

Managing Lab Operations for:

- Data Structures in JAVA.
- Introduction to Computer Science (JAVA)

Manage Subversion repository for courses

Assisting Students with course work.

Application Developer (Intern) at Polaris Software Lab

August 2007 - July 2008 (1 year)

Application Developer:

Daemon Job Scheduler to execute remote and local database jobs.

Comprehensive Database Support

Central Repository for storing and managing jobs.

User Friendly GUI / User roles authentication.

Crontab Functionality.

Environment: JAVA, J2EE, JDBC, JCrontab, Oracle 9i

Education

The University of Akron

Masters, Computer Science, 2008 - 2010

Activities and Societies: Sports Secretary of Indian Student Association

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

BTech, Information Technology, 2004 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Event coordinator for Ciencia 07 a National Level Technical Symposium

Presented technical papers and Participated at National level symposiums

Siddharth Kumar

New York, New York

Data Engineer at Facebook

Linked in Recruiter

7 people have recommended Siddharth

"Siddharth quickly became a reliable team player and leader. I look forward to working with him again."

—David Hadley, Member, Client Success Team, SearchBox, LLC, managed Siddharth at Segmint

"Sid has a passion for open source technologies (including Big Data). This passion is derived from his joy of learning new technologies. When he came to Lunexa, Sid had very limited exposure to the Hadoop ecosystem. But, by the end of his time with us he was one of our Hadoop experts. Self-driven growth is a rarity and Sid has this in spades. Last, but not least, Sid is great to work with. He has a fantastic work ethic and is a great team player. I hope our paths will cross again!"

—David Cole, Chief Customer Officer, Domino Data Lab, managed Siddharth indirectly at Claraview (formerly Lunexa, acquired in 2013)

"I worked with Siddharth at CareerBuilder in Business Intelligence. Siddharth was always more than willing to offer his assistance and expertise to help others learn quickly. He is always extremely friendly, efficient and easy to do business with. He had a vast knowledge of the systems and as a subject matter expert was able to clearly and effectively share knowledge between teams. It was an extreme pleasure working with him while I had the chance."

—Mark LaCoursiere, Agile Delivery & Transformation Coach, Elavon, Inc., worked directly with Siddharth at CareerBuilder.com

"I think the best thing I can say about Siddharth is that I would hire him back in less than one second. I think that says it all."

—Rob Heiser, Founder, Segmint, managed Siddharth indirectly at Segmint

"Siddharth is a passionate, talented and savvy person that I have had the pleasure of working with. He works hard to make sure he delivers quality and has the ability to work in many different types of environments and with different types of personalities. Siddharth utilizes his technical expertise to build solutions and solve problems. He will be a valued asset to any organization and I hope our paths cross again. All the best, Sid!"

—David Choi, Client Partner, Trianz, managed Siddharth indirectly at Claraview (formerly Lunexa, acquired in 2013)

"Siddharth is not only passionate about his work but a quick learner. He has extensive knowledge about all the available tools and technologies to develop rich, robust and scalable applications to leverage the existing platform, which makes Siddharth a good technical resource to work with."

—Abdul Khader, Senior Software Engineer, Career Builder, worked with Siddharth at CareerBuilder.com

"Siddharth displayed a good level of passion and enthusiasm for implementing and bringing Hadoop as a utility to our processes. During our shared goal, Siddharth, took many initiatives to point us in the right direction for Hadoop implementation. I will definitely recommend him as an excellent team player and a valuable asset for any organization, that he works for presently or in the future."

—Kavita Ramachandran, Business Intelligence Manager, CareerBuilder, managed Siddharth indirectly at CareerBuilder.com